Preliminary Inventory to the Robert Wallace Berry Papers, 1932-1976
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert Wallace Berry Papers,
1932-1976
75097
Berry, Robert Wallace, 1898-
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, reports, printed matter, and photographs, relating to American naval operations in World Wars I and II, and to the administration of the United States Department of Defense under Secretary of Defense James Forrestal.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Forrestal, James, 1892-1949.; United States. Dept. of Defense.; United States. Navy--Officers.; Civil defense.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Naval operations.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Military policy.
Container List
- Unpublished autobiography (Box 1)
- Roster of U.S. Asiatic Fleet, 1 April 1932 (Box 2)
- Report of investigation of Navy public relations, Hawaiian Area, 22 February 1942 to 19 March 1952
- Censorship in World War II, including the Roberts Commission report on the Pearl Harbor attack; regulations and directives for war correspondents attached to the Army, Navy, Marine Corps and Coast Guard; code of wartime practices for American press and broadcasters; and miscellaneous censorship material
- Reports of cruise of attack transport USS William K. Biddle (APA-8) from Pearl Harbor to Leyte, P.I., 1944
- First report of the secretary of defense, 1948
- First annual report on civil defense for the city of Los Angeles, 1951
- Report on Operation Doorstep by the AEC, Yucca Flat, Nevada, 17 March 1953
- Report on home shelters, USCDA, July 1953
- National Security Industrial Association, brief pictorial report and NSIA in Perspective,June 1975
- NSIA annual reports for 1948, 1958, 1967, 1968, and 1969, with list of dinner guests
- Book, in Japanese, by Cmdr Sadeo Seno, MSDF, on the cruise of the Japanese Training Squadron (Box 3)
- Four color slides of the launch of Apollo XI, 16 July 1969, taken by donor
- Public relations in the national military establishment and related studies, 1947-1948
- Bicentennial file, 1975-1976
- Photo album no. 2 (Box 4)
- Foreword to R. W. Berry's autobiography by Gen. A. C. Wedemeyer, January 1978